<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AWS CDK on The road</title><link>https://kane.mx/tags/aws-cdk/</link><description>Recent content in AWS CDK on The road</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kane.mx/tags/aws-cdk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custom compliance implementation in AWS CDK</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2024/custom-compliance-for-aws-cdk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2024/custom-compliance-for-aws-cdk/</guid><description>
AWS CDK accelerates cloud development using common programming languages to model your applications. I had a series of posts using CDK to demonstrate Building serverless web applications with AWS Serverless. Because CDK uses a programming language to model your application, you can encapsulate your library via Constructs, and then reuse it crossing the entire application.
Meanwhile, you can create your own constructs to encapsulate the compliance requirements to simplify the code.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2024/custom-compliance-for-aws-cdk/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Build serverless web application with AWS Lambda web adapter</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2023/build-serverless-web-application-with-aws-lambda-web-adapter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2023/build-serverless-web-application-with-aws-lambda-web-adapter/</guid><description>
Disclaimer: the cover image was generated by StableDiffusionXL with prompts 'cover image, spring boot, flask framework running in aws lambda'.
When deploying and operating a web application on the cloud, you prefer to use your favorite programming language and web framework. Also, you want to benefit from Serverless technologies for stability, scalability, cost optimization, and operation excellence.
AWS Lambda Web Adapter is a tool that perfectly meets your expectations. It lifts and shifts the web application based on your preferred language and web framework, including FastAPI, Flask, Django, Express.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2023/build-serverless-web-application-with-aws-lambda-web-adapter/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Define your API via OpenAPI definition on AWS</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/import-oas-as-api-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/import-oas-as-api-on-aws/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Application Programming Interfaces(APIs) is a critical part of the web service, Werner Vogel, the CTO of AWS had a great
&lt;a href="https://thenewstack.io/werner-vogels-6-rules-for-good-api-design/">6 Rules for Good API Design&lt;/a> presentation in 2021 re:Invent keynote.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In AWS the developers could manage and proxy the APIs via &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/api-gateway/">Amazon API Gateway&lt;/a>. The developers can use
console, CLI, API or IaC code(for example, Terraform/CloudFormation/CDK) to provisioning the API resources on AWS.
However some developers might flavor with using &lt;a href="https://oai.github.io/Documentation/">OpenAPI specification&lt;/a> to define the APIs. It enables multiple services/tools
to understand the APIs' specification, such as Postman. Amazon API Gateway supports this use case, you can import the
existing OpenAPI definition as API.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/import-oas-as-api-on-aws/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setup DevOps pipeline with few code</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/devops-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/devops-pipeline/</guid><description>
&lt;p>DevOps pipeline is a key component of project operation,
it helps you automate steps in your software delivery process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Amazon itself has rich expirence on DevOps with large scale services,
it &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/builders-library/?nc1=h_ls&amp;amp;cards-body.sort-by=item.additionalFields.sortDate&amp;amp;cards-body.sort-order=desc&amp;amp;awsf.filter-content-category=content-category%23software-delivery-operations&amp;amp;awsf.filter-content-type=*all&amp;amp;awsf.filter-content-level=*all">shares the lesson and learn&lt;/a> from operating the Amazon's services.
You can read &lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2020/the-best-practise-of-deployment-at-amazon/">this summary post&lt;/a> written in Chinese.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also AWS provides fully managed SaaS services for the lifecycle of software development, including
&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/codepipeline/">AWS CodePipeline&lt;/a> for automating continuous delivery pipelines,
&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/codecommit/">AWS CodeCommit&lt;/a> for securely hosting highly scalable private Git repositories,
&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/codeartifact/">AWS CodeArtifact&lt;/a> for artifact management,
&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/codebuild/">AWS CodeBuild&lt;/a> for building and testing code with continuous scaling and
&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/codedeploy/">AWS CodeDeploy&lt;/a> for automating code deployments to maintain application uptime.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/devops-pipeline/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Federated OIDC login with Cognito and Amplify</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/federated-oidc-login-with-cognito-and-amplify/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/federated-oidc-login-with-cognito-and-amplify/</guid><description>
&lt;p>When working on either 2C application or 2B service, the customers do not want to
or is not allowed to sign up the new account, they can login the application via existing
IdP or enterprise SSO. So, building the application supports the federated OIDC login
to address such requirements.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post extends the capability of &lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/protect-website-with-cognito/">Todolist application protected by Amazon Cognito&lt;/a>,
using &lt;a href="https://auth0.com/">Auth0&lt;/a> as the third party &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenID">OpenID Connect&lt;/a> provider introduces the external user pool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/federated-oidc-login-with-cognito-and-amplify/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Protect website with Cognito</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/protect-website-with-cognito/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/protect-website-with-cognito/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/static-website/">Previous post&lt;/a> we demonstrated how distributing and securely deploying the website to global end users.
The authentication and authorization are always mandatory features of web application.
&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cognito/">Amazon Cognito&lt;/a> is a managed AWS serverless service helping the applications to implement AuthN and AuthZ,
with Cognito the applications securely scales to millions of users(up to 50,000 free users)
supporting identity and access management standards, such as OAuth 2.0, SAML 2.0, and OpenID Connect.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/protect-website-with-cognito/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Distribute the website globally</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/static-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/static-website/</guid><description>
&lt;p>It's a well known pattern to distribute the website via CDN globally,
it reduces the latency of the site and improve the availibity and security leveraging the infrastructure of cloud provider.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using CDN service &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudfront/">CloudFront&lt;/a> and simple storage &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s3/">S3&lt;/a> on AWS hosts the static website.
It well fits the SPA(single page application) framework technologies, for example, React, Vue and Angularjs.
There are lots of existing project and code snippets to sharing this pattern,
such as &lt;a href="https://serverlessland.com/patterns/cloudfront-s3-lambda-cdk">CloudFront to S3 and API Gateway&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/cdk-patterns/serverless/blob/main/s3-react-website/README.md">AWS S3 / React Website Pattern&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/static-website/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Build no code restful HTTP API with API Gateway and DynamoDB</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/restful-api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/restful-api/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Most web applications are using &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Representational_state_transfer">Restful APIs&lt;/a> to interactive with the backend services.
In the TODO application, it's the straight forward to get, update and delete the items from backend database.
&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/dynamodb/">Amazon DynamoDB&lt;/a> is a key-value database, it fits for this scenario with scalability and optimized pay-as-you-go cost.
Also &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/api-gateway/">Amazon API Gateway&lt;/a> has built-in integration with AWS serivces, the restful API can be transformed to
the request to DynamoDB APIs. Using this combination you can provide the restful APIs only provisioning AWS resources
without writing the CRUD code!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/build-serverless-app-on-aws/restful-api/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Publish your AWS CDK applications via AWS CloudFormation templates</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publish-cdk-app-via-cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publish-cdk-app-via-cloudformation/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/">AWS CDK&lt;/a> is a great abstract to accelerate managing the cloud infrastructure as code.
The journey will be enjoyful with leveraging the &lt;a href="https://constructs.dev/">Construct Hub&lt;/a> to use the high level contributions from AWS partners and commnunity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/?nc1=h_ls">AWS CloudFormation&lt;/a> is one of the underly technologies of AWS CDK to manage the cloud infrastructure.
It easily to enable the IT administrators even business operators whom has no/limited developer skills to
develop the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/solutions/browse-all/">end-to-end solutions&lt;/a> with one-click user experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it's a use case for effectively developing the &lt;strong>Cloud Application&lt;/strong> via AWS CDK,
then publishing it as CloudFormation template with better user experimental experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publish-cdk-app-via-cloudformation/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Publishing npm packages to multiple registries with Projen</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publishing-npm-packages-to-multiple-registries-with-projen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publishing-npm-packages-to-multiple-registries-with-projen/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://constructs.dev/">Construct Hub&lt;/a> is a web portal to collect the &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cdk/latest/guide/constructs.html">constructs&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/">AWS CDK&lt;/a>, CDK8s and CDKtf.
The construct could support multiple programming languages, such as Javascript/TypeScript, Python, Java and C#.
Actually the construct is developed by TypeScript, then it's compiled as across languages library by &lt;a href="https://aws.github.io/jsii/">jsii&lt;/a>!
Any npm/pypi package with certain tags will be discovered by Construct Hub, the package will be automatically recognized as
construct package and listed in Construct Hub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/projen/projen">Projen&lt;/a> is a project generator to create project with simplifying the project configuration to support dependencies management,
building, unit testing, code style linting, CI/CD via Github actions PR and actions. So &lt;a href="https://projen.io/awscdk-construct.html">projen&lt;/a>
supports the construct project out of box, which configures construct project with jsii configuration
that build the construct to across languages library, though publish the packages
to kinds of package registries, such as npmjs, pypi and maven central.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publishing-npm-packages-to-multiple-registries-with-projen/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The update of Sonatype Nexus repository OSS on AWS solution</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2021/nexus-oss-on-aws-v110-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2021/nexus-oss-on-aws-v110-update/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last year I shared the production-ready, cloud native solution to &lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2020/deploy-sonatype-nexus-oss-on-eks/">deploy Sonatype Nexus Repository OSS on AWS&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2021/nexus-oss-on-aws-v110-update/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>在AWS上快速部署专用的NAT实例</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2021/simple-nat-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2021/simple-nat-on-aws/</guid><description>
&lt;p>本方案的起因是，一个源代码托管在Github上的项目fix一个重要的bug后，在AWS上的持续部署流水线一直失败。分析日志后，发现流水线中的数个步骤需要克隆源代码，但是访问Github的网络非常不稳定，这数个流水线任务持续因连接超时，连接拒绝等网络错误而失败。而流水线任务大量使用了CodeBuild, Lambda等AWS托管服务，无法为执行环境配置可靠的网络连接。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2021/simple-nat-on-aws/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Effective AWS CDK for AWS CloudFormation</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2020/effective-aws-cdk-for-aws-cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2020/effective-aws-cdk-for-aws-cloudformation/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infrastructure_as_code">Infrastructure as Code&lt;/a> is the trend to manage the resources of application. &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/">AWS CloudFormation&lt;/a> is the managed service offering the IaC capability on AWS &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/cloudformation-create-your-aws-stack-from-a-recipe/">since 2011&lt;/a>. CloudFormation uses the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Declarative_programming">declarative language&lt;/a> to manage your AWS resources with the style what you get is what you declare.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However there are cons of CloudFormation as a declarative language,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the readability and maintenance for applications involving lots of resources&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the reuseable of code, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/mt/introducing-aws-cloudformation-modules/">CloudFormation modules&lt;/a> released in re:Invent 2020 might help mitigate it&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/">AWS CDK&lt;/a> provides the programming way to define the infra in code by your preferred programming languages, such as Typescript, Javascript, Python, Java and C#. AWS CDK will synthesis the code to CloudFormation template, then deploying the stack via AWS CloudFormation service. It benefits the Devops engineers manage the infra on AWS as programming application, having version control, code review, unit testing, integration testing and CI/CD pipelines, the deployment still depends on the mature CloudFormation service to rolling update the resources and rollback when failing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For solution development, using CDK indeed improves the productivity then publish the deployment assets as CloudFormation templates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Though CDK application can be synthesized to CloudFormation template, there are still some differences blocking the synthesized templates to be deployed across multiple AWS regions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post will share the tips on how effectively writing AWS CDK application then deploying the application by CloudFormation across multiple regions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2020/effective-aws-cdk-for-aws-cloudformation/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>跨账号跨区域部署AWS CDK编排的应用</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2020/deploy-aws-cdk-applications-cross-accounts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2020/deploy-aws-cdk-applications-cross-accounts/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/">AWS CDK&lt;/a>是编排部署AWS云上资源最佳的工具之一。基于AWS CDK的应用应该如何实践DevOps持续集成和部署呢？&lt;/p>
&lt;p>通常我们有下面几种方法，&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2020/deploy-aws-cdk-applications-cross-accounts/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Deploy Sonatype Nexus repository OSS on EKS</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2020/deploy-sonatype-nexus-oss-on-eks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2020/deploy-sonatype-nexus-oss-on-eks/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.sonatype.com/nexus-repository-oss">Sonatype Nexus repository OSS&lt;/a> is an artifact repository that supports most software repositories such as Maven, Pypi, Npmjs, Rubygems, Yum, Apt, Docker registry and etc. In the enterprise Nexus repository is widely used for storing proprietary artifacts and caching the artifacts for speeding up the devops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2020/deploy-sonatype-nexus-oss-on-eks/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AWS CDK简介</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infrastructure_as_code">Infrastructure as Code&lt;/a>(架构即代码)一直是衡量公有云是否支持良好运维能力的重要指标。作为云计算领先的AWS，通过服务&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cn/cloudformation/">CloudFormation&lt;/a>来编排云环境中的基础设施资源。不过由于CloudFormation是使用YAML/JSON编写的声明式语言，不善于处理逻辑，编写繁琐且不利于调试排错，对于新上手的Devops工程师来说也有不小的学习曲线。三方开源的工具&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terraform_(software)">Terraform&lt;/a>同样没有很好解决&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cn/cloudformation/">CloudFormation&lt;/a>存在的这些问题。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>无服务器架构的域名重定向服务</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/effective-cloud-computing/serverless-domain-redirect/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/effective-cloud-computing/serverless-domain-redirect/</guid><description>
&lt;p>业务时常有需求将某个域名(A)的访问重定向到其他域名(B)，即使实现这样一个很简单的需求通常也需要部署Web服务器（例如Nginx），为域名A的请求返回302响应，并提供新的Location地址重定向到域名B。现在基于云计算服务，我们可以使用一些托管服务来实现同样的事情，无需管理服务器和维护应用，同时做到最低成本实现该需求。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>接下来将介绍如何利用AWS上的服务实现该需求。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/effective-cloud-computing/serverless-domain-redirect/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>