<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>trip on The road</title><link>https://kane.mx/categories/trip/</link><description>Recent content in trip on The road</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2021, Kane Zhu; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 15:11:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kane.mx/categories/trip/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Food and Drinking</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/food-and-drinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 15:11:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/food-and-drinking/</guid><description>
Honestly speaking, you have eaten the best delicious food if you're living in China. Though we have more and more concerns on the safety of food, we have to recognize that Chinese food is more delicious than others.
The cuisine is simple in Austria. People always use pork, beef, flour, tomato, potato and few green vegetables. So they surprised Chinese cost several hours to make the food.
Gulasch, it's good tasted after eating pizza several times
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/food-and-drinking/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working Workspace</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/working-workspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 17:29:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/working-workspace/</guid><description>
Joel posted a blog related to how to hire the great programmers. One of his key points is building comfortable workspaces.
I believe every programmer loves the workspace like Google and Fog Creek. The workspace of Google has been very famous due to its French chef, gymnasium and big sofas. Why is Fog Creek? It's the company created by Joel, he also practiced his theory on his company. Ruan YiFeng posted a blog for it.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/working-workspace/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transportation</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/transportation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 16:20:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/transportation/</guid><description>
Salzburg is a small city and is on the banks of the Salzach River. It's easy to go through the city by bus in 30 minutes.
Salzach River
outline view
Riding the bicycle is a very good way to enjoy the beautiful sight of the city. You could see many kids with parents riding bicycle in the sunny weekend.
The train station and a major bus transient station are the same one that is called as 'main station' by local residents.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/transportation/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working style</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/working-style/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2010 17:45:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/working-style/</guid><description>
There are 20+ staffs in Salzburg office. Most of them are developers, one is administrator of office.
Generally the staffs in Salzburg work more flexible than the staffs working in Beijing.
Some of them live in German. Even though it's not so far as Salzburg, they also need come to Salzburg by train. So sometimes they work at home, use internet and phone as communication tool.
And they have different responsibilities for products.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/working-style/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>day 1</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/day-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 19:24:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/day-1/</guid><description>
度过长途飞行的旅程不是一件容易的事。要在狭小的空间里待上近10个小时，好在是两人出行，半睡半聊的打发过了时间。
到达维也纳之后，出了登机通道看到的居然是一个酒吧类的餐馆。感觉很稀奇，也很有味道。
周围当然少不了免税店和商铺，但远没有首都机场那样的规模。总体感觉就像国内大型超市购物出口一样，而且人也不多。
另外赞一下维也纳机场的Wifi，简单配置就K了，哪像国内的，又要移动号码，还要短信获取，搞半天也没弄定。
转机之前还有段时间，就在机场里到处逛了逛。顺便在一个吧解决了晚餐，同时也尝了杯当地啤酒。
去萨尔茨堡的飞机还是带螺旋桨的，头次坐这样的老式飞机。
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/day-1/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>