<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Clickstream-Analytics on The road</title><link>https://kane.mx/series/clickstream-analytics/</link><description>Recent content in Clickstream-Analytics on The road</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kane.mx/series/clickstream-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deep dive clickstream analytic series: Serverless web console</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/deep-dive-clickstream-analytics/web-console/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/deep-dive-clickstream-analytics/web-console/</guid><description>
&lt;p>This post explores the &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/solutions/latest/clickstream-analytics-on-aws/how-the-solution-works.html#web-console">web console&lt;/a> module of the &lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/deep-dive-clickstream-analytics/preface/">clickstream solution&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The web console allows users to create and manage projects with their data pipeline, which ingests, processes, analyzes, and visualizes clickstream data. In version 1.1, the &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/solutions/latest/clickstream-analytics-on-aws/analytics-studio.html">Analytics Studio&lt;/a> was introduced for &lt;strong>business analysts&lt;/strong>, enabling them to view metrics dashboards, explore clickstream data, design customized dashboards, and manage metadata without requiring in-depth knowledge of data warehouses and SQL.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/deep-dive-clickstream-analytics/web-console/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to build a clickstream analytic system for small businesses to large-scale events</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/deep-dive-clickstream-analytics/preface/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/deep-dive-clickstream-analytics/preface/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In the last couple of months, I led a team to build a comprehensive and open-sourced &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/solutions/implementations/clickstream-analytics-on-aws/">solution&lt;/a> that helps customers analyze clickstream events on the cloud. The solution provides data autonomy, allowing users full access to raw data, near real-time ingestion, flexible configurations, and cost-effectiveness. It is a system that utilizes serverless services to cater to various customers, whether small businesses or large-scale events with massive data volumes, offering fully managed services with minimal operational efforts or the flexibility to use preferred open-source technical stacks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/deep-dive-clickstream-analytics/preface/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Analyzing Clickstream Events Using Amazon Athena UDFs</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2024/analyzing-clickstream-events-using-amazon-athena-udfs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2024/analyzing-clickstream-events-using-amazon-athena-udfs/</guid><description>
&lt;p>In today's digital age, businesses are constantly seeking ways to understand and analyze user behavior on their websites. Clickstream events provide valuable insights into how users interact with a website, and analyzing this data can help businesses make informed decisions to improve user experience and drive conversions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/solutions/implementations/clickstream-analytics-on-aws/">Clickstream Analytics on AWS&lt;/a> collects, ingests, analyzes, and visualizes clickstream events from your websites and mobile applications. The solution manages an &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/solutions/latest/clickstream-analytics-on-aws/ingestion-endpoint.html">ingestion endpoint&lt;/a> to receive clickstream events, which are multiple events in a batch sent by the solution‘s SDKs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2024/analyzing-clickstream-events-using-amazon-athena-udfs/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>