<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OAuth on The road</title><link>https://kane.mx/tags/oauth/</link><description>Recent content in OAuth on The road</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kane.mx/tags/oauth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leveraging MCP Client's OAuthClientProvider for Seamless AWS AgentCore Authentication</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2025/use-mcp-client-oauthclientprovider-invoke-mcp-hosted-on-aws-agentcore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2025/use-mcp-client-oauthclientprovider-invoke-mcp-hosted-on-aws-agentcore/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Building on my &lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2025/invoke-mcp-hosted-on-aws-agentcore/">previous exploration of connecting to MCP servers hosted on AWS AgentCore&lt;/a>, I've been working extensively with the native MCP SDK's OAuth Client Provider to streamline authentication workflows. The MCP SDK's built-in OAuth support has evolved significantly, offering robust solutions for both interactive user authentication and machine-to-machine (M2M) flows.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this follow-up article, I'll share the key improvements and special techniques I've discovered for using the MCP Client's &lt;code>OAuthClientProvider&lt;/code> with AWS AgentCore, including handling AgentCore's unique behavior with 403 responses, implementing M2M authentication flows, and leveraging automatic token refresh capabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2025/use-mcp-client-oauthclientprovider-invoke-mcp-hosted-on-aws-agentcore/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How invoking remote MCP servers hosted on AWS AgentCore</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2025/invoke-mcp-hosted-on-aws-agentcore/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2025/invoke-mcp-hosted-on-aws-agentcore/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Recently, I've been exploring &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock-agentcore/latest/devguide/">AWS AgentCore&lt;/a>'s new capability to host &lt;a href="https://modelcontextprotocol.io/">Model Context Protocol (MCP)&lt;/a> servers, and I wanted to share my experience with connecting to these remote servers as a client. The Model Context Protocol is an open standard that enables AI assistants to securely connect with external data sources and tools, and AWS AgentCore provides a managed hosting environment for these servers with built-in authentication and scaling capabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article, I'll walk through the process of invoking MCP servers hosted on &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock-agentcore/latest/devguide/runtime-mcp.html">AWS AgentCore Runtime&lt;/a> or proxied via &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/bedrock-agentcore/latest/devguide/gateway.html">AgentCore Gateway&lt;/a>, covering different authentication methods, client implementation patterns, and practical considerations. What struck me most about this approach is how it bridges the gap between local development and enterprise-grade deployment while maintaining the flexibility that makes MCP so powerful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2025/invoke-mcp-hosted-on-aws-agentcore/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>