<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AWS CloudFormation on The road</title><link>https://kane.mx/tags/aws-cloudformation/</link><description>Recent content in AWS CloudFormation on The road</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kane.mx/tags/aws-cloudformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publish your AWS CDK applications via AWS CloudFormation templates</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publish-cdk-app-via-cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publish-cdk-app-via-cloudformation/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/">AWS CDK&lt;/a> is a great abstract to accelerate managing the cloud infrastructure as code.
The journey will be enjoyful with leveraging the &lt;a href="https://constructs.dev/">Construct Hub&lt;/a> to use the high level contributions from AWS partners and commnunity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="use-case">Use Case&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/?nc1=h_ls">AWS CloudFormation&lt;/a> is one of the underly technologies of AWS CDK to manage the cloud infrastructure.
It easily to enable the IT administrators even business operators whom has no/limited developer skills to
develop the &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/solutions/browse-all/">end-to-end solutions&lt;/a> with one-click user experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So it's a use case for effectively developing the &lt;strong>Cloud Application&lt;/strong> via AWS CDK,
then publishing it as CloudFormation template with better user experimental experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publish-cdk-app-via-cloudformation/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Effective AWS CDK for AWS CloudFormation</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2020/effective-aws-cdk-for-aws-cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2020/effective-aws-cdk-for-aws-cloudformation/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Infrastructure_as_code">Infrastructure as Code&lt;/a> is the trend to manage the resources of application. &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/cloudformation/">AWS CloudFormation&lt;/a> is the managed serive offering the IaC capability on AWS &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/aws/cloudformation-create-your-aws-stack-from-a-recipe/">since 2011&lt;/a>. CloudFormation uses the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Declarative_programming">declarative language&lt;/a> to manage your AWS resources with the style what you get is what you declare.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However there are cons of CloudFormation as a declarative language,&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the readability and maintanence for applications involving lots of resources&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the reuseable of code, &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/blogs/mt/introducing-aws-cloudformation-modules/">CloudFormation modules&lt;/a> released in re:Invent 2020 might help mitgate it&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/">AWS CDK&lt;/a> provides the programming way to define the infra in code by your preferred programming languages, such as Typescript, Javascripte, Python, Java and C#. AWS CDK will synthesis the code to CloudFormation template, then deploying the stack via AWS CloudForamtion service. It benefits the Devops engineers manage the infra on AWS as programming application, having version control, code review, unit testing, integration testing and CI/CD pipelines, the deployment still depends on the mature CloudFormation service to rolling update the resources and rollback when failing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For solution development, using CDK indeed improves the productivity then publish the deployment assets as CloudFormation templates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Though CDK application can be synthesized to CloudFormation template, there are still some differences blocking the synthesized tempaltes to be deployed across multiple AWS regeions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post will share the tips on how effectively writing AWS CDK application then deploying the application by CloudFormation across multiple regions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2020/effective-aws-cdk-for-aws-cloudformation/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>