<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CDK Construct on The road</title><link>https://kane.mx/tags/cdk-construct/</link><description>Recent content in CDK Construct on The road</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kane.mx/tags/cdk-construct/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build serverless web application with AWS Lambda web adapter</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2023/build-serverless-web-application-with-aws-lambda-web-adapter/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2023/build-serverless-web-application-with-aws-lambda-web-adapter/</guid><description>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Disclaimer&lt;/strong>: the cover image was generated by StableDiffusionXL with prompts 'cover image, spring boot, flask framework running in aws lambda'.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>When deploying and operating a web application on the cloud, you prefer to use your favorite programming language and web framework. Also, you want to benefit from Serverless technologies for stability, scalability, cost optimization, and operation excellence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/awslabs/aws-lambda-web-adapter">AWS Lambda Web Adapter&lt;/a> is a tool that perfectly meets your expectations. It lifts and shifts the web application based on your preferred language and web framework, including FastAPI, Flask, Django, Express.js, Next.js, Spring Boot, Nginx, PHP, Rust, Golang Gin, Laravel, ASP.NET, and so on! You don't have to change any code to migrate your application to Lambda runtime. It also supports WebSocket and streaming features that work well with your LLM applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2023/build-serverless-web-application-with-aws-lambda-web-adapter/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Publishing npm packages to multiple registries with Projen</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publishing-npm-packages-to-multiple-registries-with-projen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publishing-npm-packages-to-multiple-registries-with-projen/</guid><description>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://constructs.dev/">Construct Hub&lt;/a> is a web portal to collect the &lt;a href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/cdk/latest/guide/constructs.html">constructs&lt;/a> for &lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2019/aws-cdk/">AWS CDK&lt;/a>, CDK8s and CDKtf.
The construct could support multiple programming languages, such as Javascript/TypeScript, Python, Java and C#.
Actually the construct is developed by TypeScript, then it's compiled as across languages library by &lt;a href="https://aws.github.io/jsii/">jsii&lt;/a>!
Any npm/pypi package with certain tags will be discovered by Construct Hub, the package will be automatically recognized as
construct package and listed in Construct Hub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/projen/projen">Projen&lt;/a> is a project generator to create project with simplifying the project configuration to support dependencies management,
building, unit testing, code style linting, CI/CD via Github actions PR and actions. So &lt;a href="https://projen.io/awscdk-construct.html">projen&lt;/a>
supports the construct project out of box, which configures construct project with jsii configuration
that build the construct to across languages library, though publish the packages
to kinds of package registries, such as npmjs, pypi and maven central.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2022/publishing-npm-packages-to-multiple-registries-with-projen/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>在AWS上快速部署专用的NAT实例</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/2021/simple-nat-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/2021/simple-nat-on-aws/</guid><description>
&lt;p>本方案的起因是，一个源代码托管在Github上的项目fix一个重要的bug后，在AWS上的持续部署流水线一直失败。分析日志后，发现流水线中的数个步骤需要克隆源代码，但是访问Github的网络非常不稳定，这数个流水线任务持续因连接超时，连接拒绝等网络错误而失败。而流水线任务大量使用了CodeBuild, Lambda等AWS托管服务，无法为执行环境配置可靠的网络连接。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/2021/simple-nat-on-aws/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>