<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>salzburg on The road</title><link>https://kane.mx/tags/salzburg/</link><description>Recent content in salzburg on The road</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © 2021, Kane Zhu; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 15:11:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kane.mx/tags/salzburg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Food and Drinking</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/food-and-drinking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2010 15:11:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/food-and-drinking/</guid><description>
Honestly speaking, you have eaten the best delicious food if you're living in China. Though we have more and more concerns on the safety of food, we have to recognize that Chinese food is more delicious than others.
The cuisine is simple in Austria. People always use pork, beef, flour, tomato, potato and few green vegetables. So they surprised Chinese cost several hours to make the food.
Gulasch, it's good tasted after eating pizza several times
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/food-and-drinking/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Working Workspace</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/working-workspace/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 17:29:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/working-workspace/</guid><description>
Joel posted a blog related to how to hire the great programmers. One of his key points is building comfortable workspaces.
I believe every programmer loves the workspace like Google and Fog Creek. The workspace of Google has been very famous due to its French chef, gymnasium and big sofas. Why is Fog Creek? It's the company created by Joel, he also practiced his theory on his company. Ruan YiFeng posted a blog for it.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/working-workspace/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Transportation</title><link>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/transportation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2010 16:20:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/transportation/</guid><description>
Salzburg is a small city and is on the banks of the Salzach River. It's easy to go through the city by bus in 30 minutes.
Salzach River
outline view
Riding the bicycle is a very good way to enjoy the beautiful sight of the city. You could see many kids with parents riding bicycle in the sunny weekend.
The train station and a major bus transient station are the same one that is called as 'main station' by local residents.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://kane.mx/posts/archive/blogspot/transportation/">Read More&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>